{
  "CPT211": {
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "An access specifier that is made available to all member functions is",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "public"
      },
      {
        "question": " An example of modular programming paradigm is",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "procedure programming",
          "object programming",
          "structural programming",
          "high level programming"
        ],
        "answer": "structural programming"
      },
      {
        "question": "The only way to access object's data is to call it's?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": ["class", "method", "the object", "member function"],
        "answer": "member function"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the size of (bool) _____ byte(s)?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "1"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the full meaning of OOAD ____?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "object oriented analysis and design"
      },
      {
        "question": "Default datatype of C++ is ___?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "void"
      },
      {
        "question": "The keyword that preceed a className is ____?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "class"
      },
      {
        "question": "Default Method of C++ is ___?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "main"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who developed C++",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "bjarne stroustrup"
      },
      {
        "question": "What will be the output of this Program ?",
        "type": "code",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "20",
        "code": " #include &lt;iostream&gt;<br /> using namespace std; <br /> int x = 4, y = 9; <br />      int z; <br /> int main() { <br /> z = (x++) + (--y) + y; <br />cout &lt;&lt; z; <br />}"
      },
      {
        "question": " In C++, what is the sign of charater data type by default ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "signed",
          "unsigned",
          "implementation dependent",
          "none of this"
        ],
        "answer": "implementation dependent"
      },
      {
        "question": "What will be the output of this Program ? ",
        "type": "code",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "12",
        "code": "int result = 13 - 2 * 8 / 4 % 3;"
      },
      {
        "question": "The datatype known to c++ compiler are called ____?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "primitive datatype"
      },
      {
        "question": "Where does the execution of the program starts ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "User-defined function",
          "Main function",
          "None of the mentioned",
          "Void function"
        ],
        "answer": "main function"
      },
      {
        "question": "A class relate with other class through ___ ?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "inheritance"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the size of float ___byte(s)?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "4"
      },
      {
        "question": " In C++ objects we can access data members and member functions by using ____?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "dot operator"
      },
      {
        "question": "Default data type of class is_____ ?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "user defined"
      },
      {
        "question": "Is <b>strings</b> a fundamental datatype",
        "type": "option",
        "options": ["false", "true"],
        "answer": "false"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the upper limit of unsigned char ___ ?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "255"
      }
    ],
    "numberOfQuestionsToBeAnswered": 5,
    "timeInMins": "1"
  },
  "PHY214": {
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Which one of these is false about a themometric liquid ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "It must be a good conductor of heat",
          "It must have a high a specific heat capacity",
          "it must expand and contrast uniformly and steady",
          "It must have a high coefficient of expansion"
        ],
        "answer": "it must have a high a specific heat capacity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Thermometer that makes use of a given mass of gas where pressure varies with temperature at constant volume is a ___ ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "Pressure gas thermometer",
          "Gas thermometer",
          "Constant volume gas Thermometer",
          "Themometric Thermometer"
        ],
        "answer": "constant volume gas thermometer"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a property of a alcohol as a thermometric liquid",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "It boils at 78<sup>o</sup>C",
          "It solidifies at -116<sup>o</sup>C",
          "Alcohol wets glass",
          "Alcohol has high Specific Heat Capacity"
        ],
        "answer": "it solidifies at -116<sup>o</sup>c"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a property of mecury as a thermometric liquid",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "It boils at 357 degree celcius",
          "It does not wet glass",
          "It is opaque",
          "It has high Specific Heat Capacity"
        ],
        "answer": "it has high specific heat capacity"
      },
      {
        "question": "Convert 57<sup>o</sup>F to <sup>o</sup>C",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "11.11 <sup>o</sup>C",
          "25.00 <sup>o</sup>C",
          "32 <sup>o</sup>C",
          "-57 <sup>o</sup>C"
        ],
        "answer": "11.11 <sup>o</sup>c"
      },
      {
        "question": "A brass measuring scale is exactly 2m long at 15<sup>o</sup>C. Determine its length at 40<sup>o</sup>C (linear expansivity of a metal is 2.0 x 10<sup>-5 o</sup>C<sup>-1</sup>)",
        "type": "option",
        "options": ["2.0000945m", "0.00095m", "2.009m", "2.000945m"],
        "answer": "2.000945m"
      },
      {
        "question": "If the linear expansivity of a metal is 2.0 x 10<sup>-5 o</sup>C<sup>-1</sup>. Calculate the approximate value of its superficial expansivity ? ",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "4.0 x 10<sup>-5 o</sup>C<sup>-1</sup>",
          "2.0 x 10<sup>-10 o</sup>C<sup>-1</sup>",
          "4.0 x 10<sup>-10 o</sup>C<sup>-1</sup>",
          "2.0 x 10<sup>-5 o</sup>C<sup>-1</sup>"
        ],
        "answer": "4.0 x 10<sup>-5 o</sup>c<sup>-1</sup>"
      },
      {
        "question": "All these are importance of expansion effect except ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "Riverting two metals",
          "Construction of automatic fire alarms",
          "Thermostat in order to maintain steady temperature",
          "Joining two metals"
        ],
        "answer": "joining two metals"
      },
      {
        "question": "The study of heat mearsurement is _____ ?",
        "type": "german",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "calometry"
      },
      {
        "question": "The amount of heat required to raise the temperature of a substance by one Kelvin is ____ ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "Specific Heat Capacity",
          "Heat",
          "Energy",
          "Heat Capacity"
        ],
        "answer": "heat capacity"
      },
      {
        "question": "If the specific heat capacity of a unit of a substance is 430J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C. what is the Heat Capacity of 5kg of the subtance at 20<sup>o</sup>C",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "4.3 x 10<sup>4</sup>J/K",
          "6.3 x 10<sup>5</sup>J/K",
          "7.3J/K",
          "2.15 x 10<sup>3</sup>J/K"
        ],
        "answer": "2.15 x 10<sup>3</sup>j/k"
      },
      {
        "question": "The heat in joules required to raise the temperature of 1Kg of a substance by 1K/<sup>o</sup>C is ____?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "Specific Heat Capacity",
          "Heat",
          "Specific Heat",
          "Heat Capacity"
        ],
        "answer": "specific heat capacity"
      },
      {
        "question": "How much heat is needed to bring 10g of water from 50<sup>o</sup> to boiling point _____ ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": ["4200J", "2100J", "2.1 x 10<sup>6</sup>J", "2.1J"],
        "answer": "2100j"
      },
      {
        "question": "To a 1Kg sample of wood 40KJ of heat is added. Its temperature is found to rise from 20<sup>o</sup>C to 40<sup>o</sup>C. What is the specific heat capacity of the wood__?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "160J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C",
          "1670J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C",
          "800000J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C",
          "800J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C"
        ],
        "answer": "1670j/kg<sup>o</sup>c"
      },
      {
        "question": "The resistance of a Platinium wire at 0<sup>o</sup>C is 10.44 ohms and 10.71 ohms at 100<sup>o</sup>C. calculate the temperature when the resistance is 9.61 ohms?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "-307.4<sup>o</sup>C",
          "-407.4<sup>o</sup>C",
          "-9.61<sup>o</sup>C",
          "-109.61<sup>o</sup>C"
        ],
        "answer": "-307.4<sup>o</sup>c"
      },
      {
        "question": "A square sheet of 15cm<sup>2</sup> at 0<sup>o</sup>C determine it area at 40<sup>o</sup>C given the coefficient of linear expansivity of steel is (1.1x10<sup>-5 o</sup>C)",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "6.6 x 10 <sup>-5</sup>cm<sup>2</sup>",
          "15.0132cm<sup>2</sup>",
          "15.00132cm<sup>2</sup>",
          "15.12cm<sup>2</sup>"
        ],
        "answer": "15.0132cm<sup>2</sup>"
      },
      {
        "question": "A density glass bottle contains 44.25g of a liquid at 0<sup>o</sup>C and 42.02g at 50<sup>o</sup>C. calculate the real cubic expansivity ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "0.00107 K<sup>-1</sup>",
          "0.00109 K<sup>-1</sup>",
          "44.20107 K<sup>-1</sup>",
          "44.20109 K<sup>-1</sup>"
        ],
        "answer": "0.00109 k<sup>-1</sup>"
      },
      {
        "question": "A relative density bottle of 50cm<sup>3</sup> is completely filled with a liquid at 30<sup>o</sup>C its then heated to 80<sup>o</sup>C such that 0.75cm<sup>2</sup> of liquid is expelled. Calculate the apparent cubic expansivity of the liquid?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "0.0000305K<sup>-1</sup>",
          "0.000305K<sup>-1</sup>",
          "50.000305K<sup>-1</sup>",
          "50.000305K<sup>-1</sup>"
        ],
        "answer": "0.000305k<sup>-1</sup>"
      },
      {
        "question": "A piece of copper 0.1Kg is heated to 100<sup>o</sup>C and then transferred to a well lagged copper can of mass 0.05Kg containing 0.2Kg of water at 10<sup>o</sup>C. Calculate the final temperature of the mixture ?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "14<sup>o</sup>C",
          "11<sup>o</sup>C",
          "28<sup>o</sup>C",
          "24<sup>o</sup>C"
        ],
        "answer": "14<sup>o</sup>c"
      },
      {
        "question": "Calculate the power rating of an immersion heater used for 10mins to increase the temperature of 10kg by 15K(shc of water 4200J/KgC)",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "6.3 x 10<sup>6</sup>Watts",
          "6300Watts",
          "1050Watts",
          "1000Watts"
        ],
        "answer": "1050watts"
      },
      {
        "question": "A heating coil rated at 1000W is used to boil off 0.5Kg of boiling water what is the time taken to boil off the water (L<sub>v</sub> = 2.3 x 10 <sup>6</sup> J/Kg)?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "1.15 x 10<sup>3</sup>s",
          "1.15 x 10<sup>6</sup>s",
          "2s",
          "1.15 x 10<sup>9</sup>s"
        ],
        "answer": "1.15 x 10<sup>3</sup>s"
      },
      {
        "question": "What amount of current will pass through 10ohms coil if it takes 21secs to melt a lump of ice of mass 10g at 0<sup>o</sup>C if there are no loss?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": ["16 Ampere", "18 Ampere", "2 Ampere", "4 Ampere"],
        "answer": "4 ampere"
      },
      {
        "question": "A piece of iron mass 0.2Kg is heated to 64<sup>o</sup>C and gently drop into 0.15kg of water at 16<sup>o</sup>CC. if the temperature of the mixture is 22<sup>o</sup>C what is the specific heat capacity of iron?",
        "type": "option",
        "options": [
          "180J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C",
          "18J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C",
          "213J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C",
          "450J/Kg<sup>o</sup>C"
        ],
        "answer": "450j/kg<sup>o</sup>c"
      }
    ],
    "numberOfQuestionsToBeAnswered": 20,
    "timeInMins": "10"
  }
}
